Mohamad Faruk

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am a web developer specialising in front-end development and UX/UI design. I love the process of creating innovative and performant applications that add value to people's lives. This passion has propelled me to learn a vast range of technologies with the aim of creating solutions to difficult problems.

Check out my personal website (found below) to see my portfolio projects.

CONTACT

- o mohamadfaruk@live.com
- 07956 255 101
- o www.mohamadfaruk.com
- github.com/mohfaruk

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

ROMAN POST

May 2021 - present

Designed a modern accessible business website utilising HTML, Sass and JavaScript. Applied structure to the webpage using Bootstrap. The website acted as the businesses online presence and as a result experienced a surge of customers.

As part of this role, I met with clients to determine website needs and follows up with regular conversations and updates. I would also create website layouts with computer or handmade sketches to organise information and allow for intuitive usage. Following this, I built the website according to client specifications by writing code, designing pages and widgets, and incorporating graphics and video elements

Case Coordinator

NURSING & MIDWIFERY COUNCIL

March 2018 - April 2022

Manage and process cases & complex legal documentation in accordance with regulatory law, whilst complying to GDPR principles.

Job Support Advisor

ATTEND ABI

January 2016 - January 2017

Support clients in their return to employment by holding regular face-toface discussions, source prospective employment opportunities and checking clients employment documents

EDUCATION

Self Led Web Development Framework

ZERO TO MASTERY ACADEMY (ONLINE)

October 2020 - June 2021

BSc (Hons) Pychology - Upper Second Class Honours

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER

September 2014 - July 2017

Extended Diploma in ICT - Triple Distinction

CITY AND ISLINGTON COLLEGE

September 2011 - June 2013

LANGUAGES

HTML & CSS JavaScript React JS Node JS

TOOLS & SKILLS

Node Package Manager Git/Git Workflow Sass Bootstrap Tailwind